so let's consider the example of this
program here where we do an ad and then
we should branch to the label but
instead we mispredicted and go to a
divide and we really should have
executed this multiply as far as the
processor is concerned it could look
like we first did this then we did this
then we finally did this resolve the
branch undone this done this so at some
given point in time the processor sees
maybe this is fully executed but not
committed at that same point in time
only this instruction is percepts
committed so the programmer sees just
this is done if the program finishes
this until the processor finishes this
here the programmer is not gonna see
that as executed so the programmer never
really sees for example this divide
because by the time the programmer sees
something after the branch executes the
branch completes execution and at that
point we kill the divide we remove it
from the rope so the programmer will
finally see the branch execute but after
that the processor will start fetching
from here so the next thing the
programmer sees is this so the
programmer never really sees execution
of any wrong path instructions and on
exceptions the programmer never sees and
instructions other than those that
should have been executed so basically
this commit is really kind of the
officially executed whereas the actual
execution before we broadcast the result
is simply kind of the internal state of
the processor that is maybe not
reflected to the outside world until we
are sure that everything is fine with
the result